<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>plot on A Megan website</title>
    <link>/tags/plot/</link>
    <description>Recent content in plot on A Megan website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/plot/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Explore income inequality in Canadian cities: an interactive map of 2001- 2016 Gini coefficient data</title>
      <link>/2020/01/02/explore-income-inequality-in-canadian-cities-an-interactive-map-of-2001-2016-gini-coefficient-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/01/02/explore-income-inequality-in-canadian-cities-an-interactive-map-of-2001-2016-gini-coefficient-data/</guid>
      <description>Background: income inequality and health research I completed master’s research in April of 2019 on the topic of income inequality and its impacts on health in Canadian cities. As part of this project, I calculated income inequality in 130 cities for 2001 through 2011. I was also able to calculate income inequality in 2016 once the census data was released in 2018.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A very intro introduction to DPLYR, from RLadies MTL</title>
      <link>/2019/10/02/a-very-intro-introduction-to-dplyr-from-rladies-mtl/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/10/02/a-very-intro-introduction-to-dplyr-from-rladies-mtl/</guid>
      <description>Last month, on a break during my workday, I decided to google some communities where I could practice and learn to code in R. It had been on my mind for a while, as I’ve had many side project ideas and occasionally get stuck from small errors !
~R Ladies~ I came across R Ladies - a community of women (and other folks) in Montreal that meet once a month to learn something new in R!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello R Markdown</title>
      <link>/2015/07/23/hello-r-markdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2015 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/07/23/hello-r-markdown/</guid>
      <description>R Markdown This is an R Markdown document. Markdown is a simple formatting syntax for authoring HTML, PDF, and MS Word documents. For more details on using R Markdown see http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com.
You can embed an R code chunk like this:
summary(cars) ## speed dist ## Min. : 4.0 Min. : 2.00 ## 1st Qu.:12.0 1st Qu.: 26.00 ## Median :15.0 Median : 36.00 ## Mean :15.4 Mean : 42.98 ## 3rd Qu.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>