<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on A Megan website</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on A Megan website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing stock value with R Ladies</title>
      <link>/2020/01/21/analyzing-stock-value-with-r-ladies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/01/21/analyzing-stock-value-with-r-ladies/</guid>
      <description>This week for R Ladies we did a tutorial on stock market analysis.
This first R chunk sets up the R-Markdown environment. Within the brackets of the first line, the R code is called setup. Include = FALSE (or F) means that when the R-Markdown file is run from R Studio to another file format, i.e. being knit, it does not run the code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple-a hugo theme - small edits to personalize.</title>
      <link>/2020/01/11/simple-a-hugo-theme-small-edits-to-personalize/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/01/11/simple-a-hugo-theme-small-edits-to-personalize/</guid>
      <description>Hello again! New year, and I&#39;m already getting into more complicated hugo/blogdown projects.
Over the holidays I&#39;d been blogging and encountered some (unfixable to me) issues with the first site I generated. After consultation with colleagues and many many hours on SO and various other websites, I decided to start over.
Upon reading through the blogdown book again, I decided to try one of their simple recommended themes! I went with simple-a because it looked nice and was recommended by the blogdown folks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Explore income inequality in Canadian cities: an interactive map of 2001- 2016 Gini coefficient data</title>
      <link>/2020/01/02/explore-income-inequality-in-canadian-cities-an-interactive-map-of-2001-2016-gini-coefficient-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/01/02/explore-income-inequality-in-canadian-cities-an-interactive-map-of-2001-2016-gini-coefficient-data/</guid>
      <description>Background: income inequality and health researchI completed master’s research in April of 2019 on the topic of income inequality and its impacts on health in Canadian cities. As part of this project, I calculated income inequality in 130 cities for 2001 through 2011. I was also able to calculate income inequality in 2016 once the census data was released in 2018.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A very intro introduction to DPLYR, from RLadies MTL</title>
      <link>/2019/10/02/a-very-intro-introduction-to-dplyr-from-rladies-mtl/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/10/02/a-very-intro-introduction-to-dplyr-from-rladies-mtl/</guid>
      <description>Last month, on a break during my workday, I decided to google some communities where I could practice and learn to code in R. It had been on my mind for a while, as I’ve had many side project ideas and lack any coding skills to make them happen.
~R Ladies~I came across R Ladies - a community of women (and other folks) in Montreal that meet once a month to learn something new in R!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New website!</title>
      <link>/2019/09/07/new-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/09/07/new-website/</guid>
      <description>I created a new website using Hugo! This will be a slow process to figure out, but I&#39;m hoping to make it my long-term, sustained website where I can blog about learning code and share figures and stories related to my research.
See ya soon, Megan</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Plain Markdown Post</title>
      <link>/2016/12/30/a-plain-markdown-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2016 21:49:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/12/30/a-plain-markdown-post/</guid>
      <description>This is a post written in plain Markdown (*.md) instead of R Markdown (*.Rmd). The major differences are:
 You cannot run any R code in a plain Markdown document, whereas in an R Markdown document, you can embed R code chunks (```{r}); A plain Markdown post is rendered through Blackfriday, and an R Markdown document is compiled by rmarkdown and Pandoc.  There are many differences in syntax between Blackfriday&#39;s Markdown and Pandoc&#39;s Markdown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello R Markdown</title>
      <link>/2015/07/23/hello-r-markdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2015 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/07/23/hello-r-markdown/</guid>
      <description>R MarkdownThis is an R Markdown document. Markdown is a simple formatting syntax for authoring HTML, PDF, and MS Word documents. For more details on using R Markdown see http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com.
You can embed an R code chunk like this:
summary(cars)## speed dist ## Min. : 4.0 Min. : 2.00 ## 1st Qu.:12.0 1st Qu.: 26.00 ## Median :15.0 Median : 36.00 ## Mean :15.4 Mean : 42.98 ## 3rd Qu.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>